

Roland Radzimski

Senior Test Automation Engineer

Recommendation

Mr. Roland Radzimiński is a Senior Test Automation Engineer with over 10 years of commercial experience in the technology and finance industry.

ISTQB certified and experienced in test management, defining test strategy and execution. Currently engaged in the project for the financial industry - PayPal Alternative Payment Method for Verifone - responsible for designing and implementing test automation processes in Java, REST Assured, Jenkins CI/CD.

Mr. Roland is a communicative and open-minded person, as well as experienced Tech Lead.

Skills (0-6):

- Java 8 5
- Java 11 5
- Selenium 5
- Oracle SQL 2

- Rest API 5
- Docker 5
- Linux 5
- Unix 5

Experience

Lead Software Test Automation Engineer

EPAM (March 2020 - present)

- Designed and implemented test automation process in Java, REST Assured, Jenkins CI/CD
- Educated engineers about best practices in terms of quality.
- Acted as a technical mentor for other testers

Technologies: Java, Spring, MongoDB, REST Assured, Cucumber, AssertJ, Awaitility, Jackson, Wiremock, Compass, Jenkins CI, Postman/Insomnia, IntelliJ, SQL

Projects: PayPal Alternative Payment Method for Verifone - enable merchants to offer alternative and local payment methods (APMs) for cross border and domestic payments as well as alternative financing

Lead Software Test Automation Engineer

YAMEO (September 2018 - February 2020)

- Designed and implemented a test automation process in Java, using Fluentlenium, REST Assured, Jenkins CI and docker.
- Managed mobile app release process
- Analyzed and documented requirements
- Moderated daily, planning, refinement, retro meetings
- Collaborated with project stakeholders, tracked and reported project progress, applied mitigation plans



- Educated engineers about best practices in terms of quality
- Recruited for other QA roles
- Acted as a technical mentor for other testers

Technologies: Java, Scala, Spring, Angular, Tapestry, Docker, Tomcat, Fluentlenium/Selenium, REST Assured, AssertJ, Jcraft Jsch, Gatling, Jenkins CI, Docker, Postman/Insomnia, DBeaver, MySQL Workbench, IntelliJ, Android Studio, xcode, Kibana **Projects:** (NGO humanitarian aid distribution system consist of master-server synchronization, support of offline distribution and synchronization using Android mobile apps.

Various applications of video conference web app for customer-expert communication e.g. reporting and storing interaction artifacts of interactive insurance claims or video customer advising and support

Lead Software Test Automation Engineer

SentiOne (July 2017 - September 2018)

- Designed and implemented a test automation process in Scala, using Fluentlenium and Jenkins.
- Educated engineers about best practices in terms of quality.
- Recruited for other QA roles.
- Acted as a technical mentor for other testers.

Technologies: Scala, React, Elastic, Fluentlenium/Selenium, AssertJ, Jenkins CI, Postman/Insomnia, IntelliJ, MySQL Workbench, Kibana

Projects: Web application for customer service from social listening and sentiment analytics with online customer service integration. Monitoring online discussions regarding a given brand. Integrating social profiles within one online brand management tool. Engaging in online discussions with current or potential customers across all web channels to increase customer satisfaction.

QA Manager

TrustBuddy (March 2015 - December 2015)

QA Trainer and Consulting

Freelance (01.2011 -now)

SQA Manager

IHS(September 2012 - March 2015)

SQA Engineer

IHS (June 2007 - September 2012)



Skills

- Test planning, Test automation, Test management, Test effort estimation, Test process improvement, Exploratory testing
- Agile methodologies Scrum
- Fluentlenium/Selenium
- REST
- Assured
- Jackson
- Jenkins
- CI
- Docker
- Java
- Cucumber
- AssertJ
- Postgresql/Mysql
- Postman/Insomnia
- Kibana
- Elasticsearch
- Sentry

Courses and Certificates

- ISTQB Foundation Level
- ISTQB Advanced Level: Test Manager

Education

- 2003 2008 Technical University of Gdansk Master's Degree, Computer Science
- 2006 2009 Technical University of Gdansk
 Graduation, Information Technology Management

Languages

English C1